A Guide to the Richmond Symphony Archives, 1932-2009
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Richmond Symphony Archives 1932-2009
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M 382
42.4 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Board of the Richmond Symphony in August of 2009.
Historical Information
Virginia's capital had its own symphony orchestra for a brief period in the 1930's; but the present Richmond Symphony dates from 1956, when it was founded as a community orchestra. Edgar Schenkman led the orchestra as its music director and conductor from its founding until 1971, when direction was taken over by French conductor Jacques Houtmann. The Symphony expanded greatly during Houtmann's sixteen years of leadership, achieving regional orchestra status and turning its part time "Little Symphony" into a full time Sinfonia in 1973. The first such professional symphonic ensemble to be established in Virginia, the Richmond Sinfonia proceeded to expand its schedule, particularly in the area of in school concerts for Virginia's school children. Further performing flexibility was lent by the Symphony's String, Brass, and Woodwind Ensembles. The development of student concerts and the sponsorship of youth orchestras rounded out the Symphony's extensive involvement with music education in the state.
The Richmond Symphony continues to be the largest performing arts organization in Virginia. Concert series, both classical and popular, are held in the Richmond Mosque and the Virginia Center for the Performing Arts (Carpenter Center), a downtown theater in whose renovation the Symphony took part. These and other special performances are supported by foundations, private donations, and grants from the National Endowment for the Arts and the Virginia Commission for the Arts.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence, musician files, concert programs, season plans, contracts, newspaper clippings and articles, Board meeting minutes, scrapbooks, photography, financial records and administrative documents, and audio-visual materials, chiefly from the 1980s through the 2000s, but also from earlier decades. A collection of related records, the RADA/Richmond Symphony Archives (M 257), is also held by Special Collections and Archives.
Arrangement
Collection is in alphabetical order.
Contents List
- Miscellaneous Documents 1933-1936, 1940-1941, 1959-2008 (Box 1-10)
  - African Concert Project February 1994 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Alternates 1997 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - American Symphony Orchestra undated (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Art Bank of Southside, VA October 24, 1998 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Articles of Incorporation, Richmond Symphony Foundation undated (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Articles undated (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Articles 1979-2007 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Artists 2005-2006 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Associate Conductor 1994 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Associate Conductor Search Fall 1996 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Associate Conductor Search 2000 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Associate Conductor Search Fall 2000 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Associate Conductor Search Spring 2004 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Auditions undated (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Ballet 1997-1998 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Beethoven 9 undated (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Beethoven Bash October 11, 1998 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - The Big Gig July 12, 1997 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Board of Directions Manual 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Boulders Concert September 14, 1997 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Boulders Concert June 4, 1998 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Brass Quintet, Emporia E.S (concert) April 8, 1998 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Brass Quartet, Longwood College (concert) October 7, 1997 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Brass Quintet, Strawberry Hill (concert) April 10, 1998 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Bridgewater College (concert) November 16, 1998 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Bridgewater College (concert) 1998-1999 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Bridgewater College (concert) September 25, 2000 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Budget (part one) 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Budget (part two) 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Budget/ PYE 2005-2006 (Box-folder 1:30)
  - Business Lunches undated (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Business Surveys undated (Box-folder 1:32)
  - By Laws, Revised May 24, 1990 (Box-folder 1:33)
  - By Laws, Adopted May 12, 1994 (Box-folder 1:34)
  - Calendar 2005-2006 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Candidates undated (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Candidates Schedule undated (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Capitol Concert February 7, 2002 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Carpenter Center undated (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Carpenter Center 1998-1999 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Carpenter Center, Press Conference Packet April 25, 1985 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Cathedral of the Sacred Heart May 2, 2000 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Catholic Charities December 12, 1997 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Catholic Charities November 29, 1999 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Catholic Charities November 27, 2000 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Catholic Charities 2001-2002 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Collegiate School January 1, 1998 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Can Co Op September 2005 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Certificate of Incorporation; State Corporate Commission undated (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Charles City County March 24, 2001 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Charter and Bylaws, The Richmond Symphony undated (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Chesterfield March 10, 2001 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Christie, Michael 1995-1997 (Box-folder 2:19)
  - Comments from Morgan's Visit undated (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Commonwealth Catholic Charities November 30, 1998 (Box-folder 2:21)
  - Community Advisory Group 1998 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Community Advisory Group for MRS undated (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Community Advisory Group for Paul Polivnick undated (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Composer comparison survey undated (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Concert, Messiah December7/8, 1991 (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Concert, Verdi Requiem February 22, 1992 (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Concert, James Tocco January 17/19, 1992 (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Concert, Boodell September 23/24, 1994 (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Concert, Rodriguez January 1/9, 1995 (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Conductor Evaluations undated (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Correspondence 2006-2007 (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Criteria undated (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Cultivation Concert May 15, 1999 (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Cultural Alliance, Charles City Co February 21, 1998 (Box-folder 2:35)
  - Danville March 25, 2002 (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Danville Concert Association June 6, 2000 (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Diemecke, Enrique 1992-1997 (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Director Search undated (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Dover Hall, Souvenir (tour) book of a hall in which a gala for the Richmond Symphony took place 2000 (Box-folder 2:40)
  - Emporia (concert) 1997-1998 (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Emporia (concert) August 28, 2000 (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Emporia (concert) January 16, 2002 (Box-folder 2:43)
  - Endowment Concert, Women's Club March 5, 1999 (Box-folder 2:44)
  - Ensembles 2003 (Box-folder 2:45)
  - Executive Committee February 26, 1987 (Box-folder 2:46)
  - Executive Committee March 18, 1987 (Box-folder 2:47)
  - Executive Committee April 23, 1987 (Box-folder 2:48)
  - Executive Committee June 25, 1987 (Box-folder 2:49)
  - Executive Committee July 15, 1987 (Box-folder 2:50)
  - Executive Committee August 19, 1987 (Box-folder 2:51)
  - Executive Committee October 21, 1987 (Box-folder 2:52)
  - Executive Committee December 17, 1987 (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Expenses undated (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Family Concert October 14, 1997 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Family Concert April 19, 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Family Concert, Magic Circle Mime Co. May 19, 2002 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Family/KBC Concert, Lawrence Golan March 10/11, 2001 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Family/KBC Concert, Lawrence Golan (Travel: hotel/transportation) March 10/11, 2001 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Family-RSO/Heavy November 5, 2000 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Fee Engagements/VCA Summary 945 undated (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Final Equal 1999 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Finalists undated (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Finalists Bios undated (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Finalists Presentations undated (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Fletcher, Richard 1997 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Fredericksburg 1999-2000 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Fredericksburg (concert) May 12, 2001 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Fredericksburg Chamber Music Festival 1992 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - General Information 1997-1999 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - George Mason University (concert) undated (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Ginter Park Women's Club (concert) January 7, 1998 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Ginter Park Women's Club (concert) November 13, 1999 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Ginter Park Women's Club (concert) January 12, 2000 (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Ginter Park Women's Club (concert) January 31, 2001 (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Glen Allen (concert) February 10, 2001 (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Glen Allen Ensembles February 10/17, 2001 (Box-folder 3:23)
  - Goochland High School (concert) March 8, 2002 (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Great Space (concert) May 4, 1998 (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Great Space (concert) May 18, 1998 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Ground Breakers (concert) November 18, 1999 (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Harrisonburg (concert) April 3, 2002 (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Henrico Family Concert October 9, 1998 (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Henrico Family Concert October 20, 2000 (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Hollywood Cemetery Map March 1994 (Box-folder 3:31)
  - In Harmony 1989-1998 (Box-folder 3:32)
  - In Schools 2004-2005 (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Inaugural Gala January 11/12, 2002 (Box-folder 3:34)
  - Instrumentation Sheets December4, 1998-January 10, 1999 (Box-folder 3:35)
  - Jewish Community Center (concert) September 12, 1998 (Box-folder 3:36)
  - Job Description, Master 2005-2006 (Box-folder 3:37)
  - Kicked Back Classics 1 (concert) October 17, 1999 (Box-folder 3:38)
  - Kicked Back Classics 2 (concert) undated (Box-folder 3:39)
  - Kicked Back Classics 2 (concert) January 16, 2000 (Box-folder 3:40)
  - Kicked Back Classics 3 (concert) February 27, 2000 (Box-folder 3:41)
  - Kicked Back Classics 4 (concert) March 26, 2000 (Box-folder 3:42)
  - Kicked Back Classics 5 (concert) April 16, 2000 (Box-folder 3:43)
  - Kilmarnock, Contact: Maria Lacquer March 23, 2002 (Box-folder 3:44)
  - Kinko's (900 W. Grace St.) undated (Box-folder 3:45)
  - Landmark Theater 2000/2001 (Box-folder 3:46)
  - Landmark Theater 2001/2002 (Box-folder 3:47)
  - Lawrenceville Run Out (concert) October 13/18, 1997 (Box-folder 3:48)
  - Lawrenceville Run Out (concert) April 8, 1999 (Box-folder 3:49)
  - Lawrenceville Run Out (concert) February 17, 2001 (Box-folder 3:50)
  - Lawrenceville Run Out (concert) October 27, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 3:51)
  - Leave of absences, Temporary Appointments undated (Box-folder 3:52)
  - Longwood College (concert) January, 21, 1999 (Box-folder 3:53)
  - Longwood College (concert) March 27, 1999 (Box-folder 3:54)
  - Longwood College, Music of Dance (concert) January 27, 2001 (Box-folder 3:55)
  - Longwood College (concert) January, 19, 2002 (Box-folder 3:56)
  - Lynchburg Community Concerts 1998/1999 (Box-folder 3:57)
  - Lynchburg Community Concerts April 25, 1999 (Box-folder 3:58)
  - Lynchburg Community Concerts February 18, 2002 (Box-folder 3:59)
  - Management Action Plan undated (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Martinsville Run Out (concert) March 16, 1998 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Mary Washington College 1997/1998 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Master Agreements (Agreement between Richmond Musicians Association and Richmond Symphony Incorporation) 1969-1977 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Master Agreement 1987-1990 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Master Agreement 1990-1996 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Magic Circle Mime, Arrive May 19, 2001 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Master Agreement 1993-1994 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Master Agreement 1994-1995 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Master Agreement 1995-1996 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Master Agreement 1996-1997 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Master Agreement 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Master Agreement 1998-1999 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Master Agreement 1999-2000 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Master Agreement 2000-2001 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Master Agreement 2001-2002 (Box-folder 4:16)
  - Master Agreement 2002-2003 (Box-folder 4:17)
  - Master Agreement 2003-2004 (Box-folder 4:18)
  - Master Agreement 2004-2005 (Box-folder 4:19)
  - Master Agreement 2005-2006 (Box-folder 4:20)
  - Master Agreement 2006-2008 (Box-folder 4:21)
  - Memorabilia 1972-1981 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Messiah (concert) December 6, 1997 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Messiah (concert) December 3, 2004 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Middlesex Co., In Schools (concert) undated (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Middlesex Run Out (concert) December 8, 1997 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Middlesex Run Out (concert) April 20, 1998 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Middlesex Co., In Schools (concert) October 28-November 9, 1998 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Middlesex Run Out (concert) November 4, 1998 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Middlesex Run Out (concert) November 13, 1999 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Middlesex Run Out (concert) April 1, 2000 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Middlesex (concert) November 11, 2001 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Middlesex (concert) April 28, 2001 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Middlesex, Contact: Raynelle Smith February 16, 2002 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Miscellaneous, license agreements, faxes to Audry Booth undated (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Miscellaneous, rental forms, in-school concert schedules undated (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Miscellaneous, rental forms, in-school concert schedules undated (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Miscellaneous, faxes, memos, license agreements (part one) undated (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Miscellaneous, mailing lists, cover sheets, receipts, Commissions of The Arts (part two) undated (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Miscellaneous, paperwork, sheet music undated (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Miscellaneous 1976-1985, undated (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Miscellaneous 1976-1981 (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Miscellaneous, office paper work (invoices etc.) April 5, 1981-March 8, 1988 (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Miscellaneous, paperwork (invoices, etc.) July 3, 1990, undated (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Miscellaneous 2005-2006 (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Mosque I undated (Box-folder 5:25)
  - Mosque II undated (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Mosque 1990-1991 (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Musician Advisory Group undated (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Music Director Search undated (Box-folder 5:29)
  - Music Director Search 1985-1987 (Box-folder 5:30)
  - Music Director Search 1997 (Box-folder 5:31)
  - Music Director Search Summer 1997 (Box-folder 5:32)
  - Music Director Search, Semi Finalist Information 1997-1998 (Box-folder 5:33)
  - Music Director Search, Finalist Information 1997-1999 (Box-folder 5:34)
  - Music Director Search Process undated (Box-folder 5:35)
  - Musicians Survey undated (Box-folder 5:36)
  - Music Sign-out sheets undated (Box-folder 5:37)
  - Naumberg Competition (concert) undated (Box-folder 5:38)
  - New York Gala (concert) 2004 (Box-folder 5:39)
  - Old forms (blank) undated (Box-folder 5:40)
  - Operations Committee 2005 (Box-folder 5:41)
  - Orchestra schedule and personnel 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5:42)
  - Paperwork, Office 1983-November 1987 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Paperwork, Office 1988-December 1992 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Park Davis January 14, 1999 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Photographs undated (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Pictures undated (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Pocahontas Park (concert) undated (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Pocahontas (concert) May 2000 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Pocahontas State Park (concert) May 22, 2000 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Pocahontas State Park (concert) September, 17, 2000 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Pops (concert) 1990-1991 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Possible Concert Halls 1989 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Presenter Touring Assistant Form 1990-1991 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Process 1997-1999 (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Rappahannock Foundation for the Arts (concert) January 29, 2000 (Box-folder 6:14)
  - Recordings 1985-1989 (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Recruitment 1997 (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Red Binders (papers that fell out), Negotiations 1985 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Rejection Letters undated (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Renaissance/Cornerstone 2000-2001 (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Research Report (Research conducted within a sample of the Richmond Symphony subscribers) May 3, 1978 (Box-folder 6:20)
  - To Realize a Dream (Plans to convert the Loew's Theatre into a Virginia Center for the Performing Arts (x2)) January 1980 (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Report on Audit (All folders contain the following information: Balance sheet, statement of profit and loss, receipts; Major concerts, receipts and expenditures; Junior concerts, receipts and expenditures; Out-of-town concerts.) 1933-1936 (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Resignations 1996-2000 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Richmond Ballet October 1988-February 1989 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Richmond Ballet 1998-1999 (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Richmond Landmark Theater undated (Box-folder 6:26)
  - Richmond Landmark Theater 1998-1999 (Box-folder 6:27)
  - Richmond Symphony Services INC, Merger undated (Box-folder 6:28)
  - Richmond Symphony 1932- 1934, undated (Box-folder 6:29)
  - Richmond Symphony, Misc. Programs/newsletters 1932-1936, undated (Box-folder 6:30)
  - Richmond Symphony 1933-1935, undated (Box-folder 6:31)
  - Richmond Symphony, Association/Board Member papers 1957, January 1, 1971 (Box-folder 6:32)
  - Richmond Symphony 1957-1958 (Box-folder 6:33)
  - Richmond Symphony 1958 (Box-folder 6:34)
  - Richmond Symphony 1958-1959 (Box-folder 6:35)
  - Richmond Symphony 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6:36)
  - Richmond Symphony 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6:37)
  - Richmond Symphony 1960-1961 (Box-folder 6:38)
  - Richmond Symphony 1963-1971 (Box-folder 6:39)
  - Richmond Symphony September 1, 1975 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Richmond Symphony 1985-1995 (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Richmond Symphony, Executive Committee 1985 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Richmond Symphony, Board of Directors/ Executive Committee 1900-1991 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Richmond Symphony 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Richmond Symphony, Side by Side (concert) March 9, 1998 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Richmond Symphony, Fall Concert 2001-2002/2002-2003 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Richmond Symphony, Germmana C.C. (concert) May 12, 2001 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Richmond Symphony Orchestra- Ledger-Money transactions logged here, "record of the number" 1933 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Richmond Symphony Orchestra- Ledger-Money transactions logged here, "record of the number", annual report to the treasurer 1940-1941 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Runouts (concert) 2005-2006 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Sacred Heart (concert) 2000 (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Sacred Heart, Pat Carlin (concert) May 10, 2001 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Sacred Heart (concert) May 1, 2002 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Sacred Heart (concert) May 14, 2005 (Box-folder 7:15)
  - St. Christopher's (concert) 1988 (Box-folder 7:16)
  - St. Paul Episcopal Church (concert) May 9, 2000 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - St. Paul Episcopal Church, Grant Hellmers (concert) May 16, 2001 (Box-folder 7:18)
  - St. Paul Episcopal Church (concert) 2002 (Box-folder 7:19)
  - St. Paul Episcopal Church (concert) May 8, 2002 (Box-folder 7:20)
  - Schedules, (one of two) undated (Box-folder 7:21)
  - Schedules, (two of two) undated (Box-folder 7:22)
  - Schedules 1983-2007 (Box-folder 7:23)
  - Schedules 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7:24)
  - Schedules 1991-1992 (Box-folder 7:25)
  - Schedules 1997-1998 (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Search Committee, (one of two) undated (Box-folder 7:27)
  - Search Committee, (two of two) undated (Box-folder 7:28)
  - Search Committee undated (Box-folder 7:29)
  - Search Committee 1998 (Box-folder 7:30)
  - Search Committee 1999 (Box-folder 7:31)
  - Search Committee, Rejection Letters undated (Box-folder 7:32)
  - Season (Newspaper clippings, programs and productions for the season) 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7:33)
  - Season 1960-1961 (Box-folder 7:34)
  - Season 1961-1962 (Box-folder 7:35)
  - Season 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7:36)
  - Season 1963-1964 (Box-folder 7:37)
  - Season 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7:38)
  - Season 1964-1965 (Box-folder 7:39)
  - Season 1965-1966 (Box-folder 7:40)
  - Season 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7:41)
  - Season 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7:42)
  - Season 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7:43)
  - Season 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7:44)
  - Season 1970-1971 (Box-folder 7:45)
  - Season 1971-1972 (Box-folder 7:46)
  - Season 1972-1973 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Season 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Season (Newspapers clippings, programs and productions for the season) 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Season 1976-1978 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Season 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Season 1977-1978 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Season 1978-1979 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Season 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Season 1980-1981 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Season 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Season 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8:11)
  - Season 1984-1985 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Season 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8:13)
  - Season 1986-1987 (Box-folder 8:14)
  - Season 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8:15)
  - Season 1989-1990 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - Season 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Season 1990-1991 (Box-folder 8:18)
  - Season 1991-1992 (Box-folder 8:19)
  - Season 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8:20)
  - Season 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8:21)
  - Season 1995-1996 (Box-folder 8:22)
  - Season 1998-1999 (Box-folder 8:23)
  - Season 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8:24)
  - Season 2001-2002 (Box-folder 8:25)
  - Season (One of Two) 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:26)
  - Season (Two of Two) 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:27)
  - Semi Final Round, Music Director Search undated (Box-folder 8:28)
  - Side by Side (concert) January 2005 (Box-folder 8:29)
  - Symphony Opera Ballet Gala (concert) undated (Box-folder 8:30)
  - Solicitation Permits undated (Box-folder 8:31)
  - State Corporation Commission 1992 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Staunton Run Out (concert) November 23, 1997 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Valley Symphonic Concerts May 23, 1999 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Valley Symphonic Concerts November 21, 1999 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Valley Symphonic Concerts April 8, 2001 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Valley Symphonic Concerts October 2, 2001 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - String Trio, St. Edwards November 19, 1997 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Supertile Estimates undated (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Surveys 1997 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Sweetbriar College (concert) February 23, 1999 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Symphony State Corporation Committee, Filing status, Annual reports undated (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Symphony Theater-Personnel file undated (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Tails (concert) 2001 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Tour Prospects 1989-1990 (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Tredegar (concert) 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Tredegar (concert) 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Tredegar (concert) 1999-2000 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Tredegar (concert), Ironwork 1999-2000 (Box-folder 9:18)
  - Tredegar, possible Hall Agreement undated (Box-folder 9:19)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9:20)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 1989-1990 (Box-folder 9:21)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9:22)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9:23)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9:24)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 2000-2001 (Box-folder 9:25)
  - University of Richmond (concert) 2001-2002 (Box-folder 9:26)
  - UPS Tracking Labels undated (Box-folder 9:27)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (concert) 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9:28)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (concert) 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9:29)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (concert) 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9:30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (concert) 1998-1999 (Box-folder 9:31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (concert) 2001-2002 (Box-folder 9:32)
  - Venues 2005-2006 (Box-folder 9:33)
  - Virginia Center of the Performing Arts May 1983 (Box-folder 9:34)
  - Viva la Simphonie 1979 (Box-folder 9:35)
  - Westminster Canterbury (concert) May 31, 1998 (Box-folder 9:36)
  - Wintergreen 2000-2001 (Box-folder 9:37)